This will save you personally 100 minutes every single week,
as long as you are a knowledge worker who sends emails regularly.
This is me answering the exact same email, a real
email I actually received, in two different ways.
Above, you see me typing out the response word by word,
and below, you see the brain dump method, which is where you
use dictation software to very loosely say what you want,
turn that into text, give the text to a large language model, and then
have the large language model craft a nice email for you, which you
then copy paste into your actual email client and then do a final pass.
I type at 80 to 90 words per minute, which is considered fairly fast, but
even so, the brain dump method is still about two times as fast as that.
And more importantly, it's also a lot more enjoyable, since
typing fast and without errors is quite mentally strenuous.
- and you're bound to make some errors anyway.
You're going to need two things.
A subscription to Claude or Chat GPT or something similar to that,
and a MacBook.  This will work on any MacBook.
All you have to do is open up the settings.  Then search for dictation.
It'll bring up this like keyboard dictation menu.
And then you scroll down and then all you have
to do is make sure that this thing is toggled on.
Probably also set the language to whatever your language is.
Now that dictation is enabled, whenever we press control twice, the
computer will pick up our voice and enter that as if we were typing.
So, press control twice.
Claude, I want you to start writing an email for me.  And here we go.
We're off to the races.
The only important thing to remember here is that at the
end of your email, when you've said, hey, I want you to
say this, that, and the other, you add dash dash dash dash,
make this into a nice draft.
email for me.  And then you press enter.
But the quickness isn't even the main advantage in my opinion.
The main advantage is that it is a lot more fun.
So give it a go.
Definitely try it out.
And something else to try out if you're in Melbourne
is my course where we are going to teach you to automate more of your
workflow using more sophisticated tools than just voice recording.
And rather than saving you 100 minutes a week, hopefully
we'll save you something closer to 200, 300 minutes a week.
15 seats, check it out, apply now.
If you're not in Melbourne though, you can't attend.
So maybe something you want to look into is this other course,
which is a free online course that I did with IT Masters called
practical AI for non-coders, which goes over some of the
theoretical aspects of AI for someone who isn't technical at all.
Very cool, very great online course.
- But everyone who watches this video has to
try this audio email pipeline at least once.
It has changed my life and it takes less
than five minutes to set up and test.
So, you have to do it.
It is now incumbent upon you to do it
at least once with one email this week.
And if you're not going to do it, then you have to tell me why.
You have to give me your excuse and it better be a a really good one.
If it's not a good excuse, I'm I'm
unfollowing, I'm disconnecting from you.
Those are the rules, okay?  You have to try it.
And it'll save you a lot of your life and it'll be awesome.
Those are the rules.